# Thomas Brown

53A Cologne Road, London SW11 2AH

0794 624 8561 tom.southwell.brown@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/tomsouthwellbrown

## **SUMMARY**

Statistician in the pharmaceutical industry specialising in data driven approaches to clinical development. Second follow-up sentence placeholder goes here. However, the first sentence is still in a draft state and will more than likely see further revision.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Statistician

Veramed (September 2016 - Present)

- Developing machine learning algorithms to predict clinical outcomes for patients
- Designing and analysing clinical trials in immunology and neurology
- Wrote several statistical simulations to assess operating characteristics of a study
- Presenting statistical analyses and concepts to non-statistical colleagues
- Become the in-house expert in R and data visualisation

# Sales and Membership / Sponsorship and Advertising Assistant

*University of Sydney Union (February 2014 – September 2015)* 

- Responsible for a membership program consisting of over 15,000 students
- Managed a team to run events promoting membership to the University of Sydney Union
- Developed and Maintained client relationships for a multi-channel advertising program
- Assisted with projects enhancing the on-campus experience of students

#### **EDUCATION**

# Master of Science (Medical Statistics)

London School of Hygiene and Tropical Medicine, University of London (2015 – 2016)

# Bachelor of Arts (Honours) (English)

University of Sydney (2011 - 2014)

### Exchange Student

University of Leeds (2012 - 2013)

# **SKILLS**

### R

- Extensive experience developing analyses and manipulating data in R for clinical trial data
- Sole developer for several R Shiny applications for commercial purposes
- Regarded as the principal in house expert at Veramed for all things R

# Python

- Developed machine learning algorithms in Python
- Experience with numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, and keras

## SQL

- Write SQL code for creating datasets from larger data sources
- Use SQL syntax within SAS for manipulating clinical trial data

#### Data Visualisation

• Developed both static and interactive graphics for presenting to both statistical and non-statistical audiences.

# Data Manipulation

• Able to handle unstructured and messy data to develop 'analysis ready' datasets

# Self-Learning

• Since completing a MSc, undertaking multiple pieces of continuing education independently including Stanford Online's Statistical Learning Course, nearly 50 courses on DataCamp, and frequently attended meetups and conference for statistical and programming education

# Machine Learning

- Built multiple algorithms using canonical techniques in both supervised learning and deep learning scenarios.
- Act as a consultant for clients regarding the design of machine learning algorithms

### Statistical Modelling

• Performed statistical modelling in clinical trials including Bayesian methods

# **Experimental Design**

• Designed multiple early phase exploratory clinical studies to determine drug efficacy

#### REFERENCES

Available on Request